New worlds are being born on a daily basis,
like bubbles rising to the surface.
This has been corroborated by the observation of a growing number of worlds.
The existence of the "observer" at the root of them all
has long since been predicted by scholars.
This observer has at last been discovered.
All of our drifting has been brought about by this boy, named Nagara.
That's the guy?!
Owing to his actions,
our futures have been stolen from us,
and we have been subjected to the absurdity of different worlds!
Where is this guy?!
Burn him at the stake!
He has manifested a great tragedy.
Nagara is guilty of a serious crime.
And now, in accordance with our rules,
we shall condemn him.
The coming tragedy must be prevented.
I can't wait to see what manner of judgment they pass.
We will dispatch Koumori the Convictor, of the Beatnik.
We know that he will exact a just sentence.
What's the matter?
Could you go on ahead without me?
Oh? Did you forget something?
No, there's just... something I need to do.
I see.
Hey, what are we gonna do? Stick with Hoshi?
There's nothing we can do.
We have nowhere to go. We're finished.
We've graduated.
We have to decide for ourselves what to do now.
Wow, so you can travel to other worlds in that?
Don't bother asking to come with us,
because you're not invited.
Well, that's a shame.
While I'm thinking of it,
there are other castaways who travel between worlds, right?
Yeah. Like you guys, they use power relics
or take advantage of the properties of a world.
Really? Sounds easier than I expected.
It might sound easy now,
but the ability to travel to other worlds
took many thousands of years to develop.
Ew, I can't believe it took thousands of years.
Immortality sure sounds boring.
What kind of people are the other castaways?
What if they were all like Ms. Aki?
I really wish that phony teacher would give up the act already.
She really had us going.
Who'd have thought she's our age in here?
She must have gone to our school once, too.
It's true, there are all sorts of people.
But you all possess something immensely powerful.
That ship should keep you all safe.
Whatcha reading there?
What's this? "Robinson Crusoe"?
G-Give it back!
How do you have the time?
You should stop reading that and go help Rajdhani.
Right?
Yes, that's it. Just like that.
What are you up to over here—
Yeah, that's the shortest route to take.
What are you doing with this?
Observing it.
It's quite entertaining how they're always going between the same places.
Doesn't matter if it's up or down—
they do as they please.
In the end, what do you think they always do?
I-I don't know.
They start eating each other. Until there's only one left.
Watching them makes me wonder...
might we also end up—
What are you doing?!
Setting them free!
You can't! I'm still watching them!
It's all over!
Hey, something crazy's happening on your screen.
Let's leave him to himself.
This drifting was caused by your power, Nagara.
But you don't need to feel responsible for it.
God gave you this power knowing full well what it would do.
You were being used before you even knew what was happening.
Nothing more.
A bat?
What's an exercise bar doing out here?
Wake up. Wake up, already!
You gotta wake up. Otherwise...
Who are you?
Ow!
Hey, what's your number?
U-Uh...
I asked you what your number is!
Um, 3-B, 25.
Group 3-B!
Fall in, right now!
I've noted significant issues with Number 25's productivity!
Your group will answer for this by having another 50 kilos
added to today's quota of 800!
Any problems, take them up with Number 25!
Dismissed!
Get back to work!
Ow!
Look, it's simple.
You take the blocks you get from the top and carry them down.
Nothing more.
Oh, okay.
What's going on here?
Hey! Get a move on!
R-Right, sorry.
It's about time I head back.
Hey, did you hear?
They finally found the guy
responsible for setting us adrift.
They say his name is Nagara,
and the Beatnik have determined it's because of him that the drifting is happening.
Our lives would have been so much better if it weren't for that guy.
Y-Yes?!
Mind if I sit next to you?
Huh? Oh, sure.
I'm Futatsuboshi. What's your name?
N-Naga... ta.
Nagata, that was a close one today.
Oh, yeah, sorry. Thanks for the help.
Nah, I wasn't looking for gratitude.
You just reminded me of when I was a new guy,
and before I knew it I was waking you up. Yeah...
nothing more.
Tell me, are you guys students from Shiraito Middle School No. 2 too?
You really don't know anything, do you?
Bet you're a novice castaway, huh?
Novice?
Yeah. We're all students from Shiraito Middle School No. 2.
It's been an awful long time since we were middle-schoolers, though.
Right now, we're all building that tower together. Nothing more.
What's it for?
We're trying to get to Heaven.
Heaven?
Heaven is the way out, back to our own world.
The way out? To the outside?
Of course. But it's more than just that.
We're hunting for treasure while we're at it. Yeah, nothing more.
So Heaven is the way out,
but there's also treasure?
What is the objective here, exactly?
Well, both of them. Yeah.
Okay, we're here.
This is our three-star hotel.
I'm sorry.
Huh?
Nothing. Good night.
Yeah, good night.
It's no use.
Your power won't work here.
Because that's the way I decided it would be.
Hey, I've been wondering...
Why are we carrying the blocks down?
Huh?
I mean, we're building a tower, right?
It'd make more sense if we were carrying them up.
Huh, that's just the way it is, I guess.
Maybe they're building the foundations or something.
"Or something"? You don't know?
Okay, then when will the tower be finished?
There you go, talking funny again.
It's been 200 years since I got here,
and I've never even considered that.
Huh? You've been at this for 200 years?
You shouldn't be surprised at just 200 years.
There's veterans who've been at it for over a thousand.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
Who's that?
That's Susugashira.
He's a bigshot host, who's also part of the Beatnik.
Host? Beatnik?
A host is sort of like the boss of their world.
And the Beatnik are whatcha might call a dream team,
made up of all the elites from different worlds.
They travel to different worlds and take an active part in them.
These elites are currently investigating the cause of the drifting.
Who was that?!
Huh? Me...
I've never seen one of these fall down before.
Other than one of mine, I mean. Nothing more.
It was you!
What are these?
Congrats on your starting pay!
Starting pay? This?
Okay, Nagata, it's my treat tonight!
Let's go all out! Nothing more!
I hope they pulverize this guy. Nothing more.
Yeah, sure.
I hate this guy more than anybody. Setting us all adrift like this...
How could he do such a terrible thing?!
Listen, Futatsuboshi...
Yeah?
What would you do if I was this Nagara guy?
There's no way you're anybody that awful.
I mean, Nagata, you and me are kindred spirits.
Are you new here?
Yeah, he's under me. Nothing more.
Here you are.
Hey, new guy, have you ever heard the legend of the shooting star?
Huh? No...
Word is that somewhere in this tower,
there's a room that shooting stars fall into.
Isn't that romantic?
Yeah, romantic!
If I catch a shooting star, I'm going to make a wish
that I'll meet a handsome husband in Heaven.
Just kidding!
Aww, I'm sure you'll meet someone.
Nagara has settled in nicely to this world.
And he doesn't seem to have found the truth behind Babel.
Not yet, anyway.
Can'tcha sleep, Nagata?
Not really...
Then you wanna go searching for shooting stars with me?
Huh? Right now?
I'm exhausted. Let's take a break.
You're exhausted? After just that?
Yeah, I'm at my limit.
I can't believe we're chasing some
urban legend that might not even be real.
It's okay if we don't find anything.
Huh?
The important thing is that we went looking, nothing more.
I'll betcha Hime is gonna be tickled to hear.
That's why you dragged me all the way out here?
It's important.
How deeply you believe in nonsense is important.
Because if we don't,
we won't have anything. Nothing more.
Good to go?
I'm going back.
We have an early start tomorrow.
Okay.
It's the same as building the tower.
There aren't any castaways who really believe
that we'll reach Heaven someday.
Whatcha looking at me like that for?
That's not funny.
It's the truth.
Then why are we all doing this?
I'm just a simple worker ant.
I'm happier giving in to hope like this, even if it's false.
Nothing more.
I'm not like that!
Oh, sorry, I didn't...
Nah, it's okay. Here, you can have this.
It'll cheer you up.
Okay?
Where did you...
If you don't want it, I'll—
I want it!
Found it! Thank goodness!
Ah, it's so good!
Wait, no it isn't. It's just...
Whoa! Shooting stars!
Huh?
Th-They're really here!
This is awesome!
Wait.
Pretty, aren't they?
These are bugs that emit light in the darkness of the caves.
Why do you think they do it?
I don't know, why?
They lure other bugs in with these pretty lights,
then hook them with their suspended slime.
Isn't that amazing?
No, get out of there!
Huh?
Hey, Nagara!
Where are you?!
Stop hiding and come on out!
How far did he go to set those ants free?
Oh, there! Over there!
Hey, Rajdhani!
This ant is...
Hey! I'm telling you, Nagara is somewhere close by!
Huh?
Oh, hey new guy!
All by yourself today?
Yeah.
Oh, this is for you.
It looks so good!
What is this?! It tastes awful!
Hey! What do you think you're doing?!
What are you so displeased with?
It's a wondrous sight, isn't it?
Babel, rising ever upward into Heaven.
A vacuous emptiness, built by human hands.
I didn't know.
But then I learned.
Did you find Nagara?
Yeah.
Apparently Mizuho and Yamabiko went to pick him up.
Are you sure you don't need to help them?
I wouldn't be of any use there.
Not to worry.
Nagara has the power to change worlds.
Besides, he's fine on his own now.
Is that something God told you?
I don't hear that voice anymore.
I should have done this way sooner.
Then I could have heard you a lot more clearly.
It's a bit late for that.
Nozomi!
At last, the time for us to depart has come.
This will be a journey to find our new home.
Fear not—we have our freedom!
And more importantly, we have our friendship.
Now, let's go!
Farewell.
Aren't the others worried about Nagara?
This is the place.
See that boy? He couldn't even do a back hip circle.
But after lots of practice,
he's gotten so good he can do that.
Everyone calls that boy Koumori the Bat.
I don't want to be like that.
There's no point in being able to do this.
What are you doing?
Turning this world upside down.
I have to keep moving forward to make up for everyone else.
So you knew?
Give Futatsuboshi my regards.
Hey, Nagara. You're at the top.
I'm impressed you made it here.
I wonder if you remember me.
No, who are you?
Koumori the Bat.
This world is a great big pit, turned upside down.
To keep everyone safe, I lock hope up in there.
Using my Upside-Down power, that is.
This is all my fault.
Even so, I've decided I won't run away anymore.
Because I don't want our going adrift to be a mistake.
You've changed.
Hey!
What's going on here?
Well, I guess you're all right now.
You're free.
Why did you let Nagara off?
We must not descend into madness.
Besides, Nagara is a castaway, just like ourselves.
Why didn't you pass judgment?!
Will this put a stop to all the tragedies?
There won't be any more needless tragedies.
Will that be enough to convince the others?
Without an observer,
everyone would have ended up as mere probabilities.
They have to understand
that no matter where we wind up,
we have to keep on fighting.
No one can accuse Nagara of anything—
nor will I allow them to.
The others have already left.
I see.
And they aren't coming back?
Yeah, they don't plan to.
Oh yeah, here.
Hey, what about you?
Do you also believe that we're never going home?
Has the light gone out?
Well, I...
I've decided to go on a voyage in this.
Once I've seen all the other worlds,
I'm going to crack the truth about this universe.
I don't know how far I'm going to get,
but I'm going to do as much as I can.
Rajdhani, there's nothing you can't do,
and no place you can't go.
I guarantee you that!
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, so uh...
You know that statue of Buddha you treasured so much?
Gen broke it, and I secretly replaced it with a new one.
I'm sorry. I wanted to at least apologize for that.
Just once?
That's okay. I forgive you.
Oh yeah, Nagara...
There's something I wanted to give you.
Here.
This is Monkey Hairball, the power relic you got for beating that world.
I've spent a long time trying to understand its effects,
and I finally figured it out.
What are they?
Give it a sniff.
Smells good, doesn't it?
Yeah, it smells like sunshine.
Huh? Is that all?
That's all.
But that scent will never go away,
and it will never change.
Even if you set it on fire, or boil it in curry.
No matter where it is,
or what condition it's in, it never changes.
It's the perfect power for you.
Thanks.
I'm glad we became friends.
Bon voyage!
Right back at you!
How long are you guys planning to stay on this island?
You should come with me.
Nozomi, you can't do anything,
so you'd be safer with me, right?
Nagara, you'd come too, right?
No, I won't. There's something I have to do.
What's your problem?
I'm not giving up.
Are you for real?
Don't you understand the situation?
We can never go home again.
Even so, I'm going to continue down my path.
Nothing more.
Yeah, I like that. Let's do it.
Hey Nozomi, you're in too, right?
I'm...
not sure what I'm going to do...